<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on David Hamp-Gonsalves</title>
    <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on David Hamp-Gonsalves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 10:17:20 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Human Time Tracking</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/one-mississippi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Nov 2017 10:17:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/one-mississippi/</guid>
      <description>Goal Graphs  accuracy up to 2 minutes w/wo prefix numbers by duration (show change over time) time differences of prefix&amp;rsquo;s time differences vs number of sylibles adjusted system human test results  Problem Lying in bed, at 4am, listening to my son cry. Counting one one-thousand, two one-thousand, three one-thousand&amp;hellip; till two minutes had past and I would try once again to comfort him back to sleep. I thought about how fundimentally inaccurate this method was expecting the audiable duration of one to be similiar to one hundred and thirty three.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GCN Top 10 Cycling Apps</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/gcn-top-10-apps/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/gcn-top-10-apps/</guid>
      <description>A few years back I wrote a simple launcher that took advantage of Strava&amp;rsquo;s NFC action intents to automatically start recording a ride. I created some icons for it, named it One Tap Record for Strava and put it in the Play store for others to use.
Fast forward to today, where without a single update or PR campaign the &amp;ldquo;app&amp;rdquo; has garnered 100 thousand users and was featured on GCN&amp;rsquo;s Top 10 Cycling Apps list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Rollers</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/diy-rollers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 19:51:50 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/diy-rollers/</guid>
      <description>I built a set of rollers to determine how much I enjoyed riding them. They were made from 3 inch ABS pipe, which I finished with drilled end caps, fitted with lag bolts. The bolts fit into ball bearings(scavenged from a skateboard) which were recessed into the 2x4 frame.
  This build was intended as a proof-of-concept but worked sufficiently well that a second version was not required. The only deficiency I encountered was from poorly triangulating the cap centers(I used a tape measure and hand drilled the holes) which resulted in vibration at high speeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gif Twist</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/gif-twist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:31:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/gif-twist/</guid>
      <description> I saw a interesting timelapse animation on Reddit and created Gif-Twist to automate the long manual processs (~10 hours).
Gif-Twist combines all the images of a timelapse into each output frame, displaying slices of each radiating around a central point.
Examples </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo Bike in Canada</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/cargo-bike-in-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 10:17:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/cargo-bike-in-canada/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had a Babboe cargo bike in Toronto for a year now, this is a review of that time.
I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden the Babboe every day for a year. Its terrific on the ice and works well in deep snow. Its amazingly useful, and gets my daughter to daycare and back each day. It holds about $200 in groceries plus a child. Its easy to peddle and only takes a few minutes to learn to ride (if you can already ride a bicycle).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Value Add for Being the Best</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/the-value-of-being-the-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 14:12:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/the-value-of-being-the-best/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Training data shapes our current iterations of AI and as they get more competitive so will the people who create it.
While its easy to use training data from many individuals(driving habits for example) which might average out to be the best overall it will be hard to optomize for specific attributes(gas millage, passenger comfort).
I think this will create new incentives for being the best at mundane activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircleCI vs Travis</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/circleci-vs-travis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 23:12:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/circleci-vs-travis/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Just use CircleCI.
Having used both products in my last two positions I can say that while I once pined for Travis&amp;rsquo;s(then) superior documentation, that stage has passed and I now enthusiastically choose CircleCI.
CircleCI&amp;rsquo;s UI is amazing. It feels snappy and well suited to the task. I often find myself waiting for pages to load in Travis. The UI is also branch centric which better supports feature development where as Travis seems project focused and doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit my typical usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Move To San Francisco?</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/moving-to-sf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 23:09:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/moving-to-sf/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Yes.
My move to SF is 100% a silicon valley stereotype. I wrote an app(eb), was contacted by some startups and large valley companies and a couple weeks later I was on a plane with a 6 month old and my wife.
Coming from Toronto there was almost no cultural transition, except for the dissonance between rich/poor and how strictly each cultural group / archetype stays in their own portion of the city.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2015</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/hacktoberfest-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 23:14:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/hacktoberfest-2015/</guid>
      <description>I took part in Digital Oceans Hacktoberfest &amp;amp; had a lot of fun. I ended up pushing some PR&amp;rsquo;s to new projects that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have otherwise and got a a t-shirt even though I live in Canada (usually these things are US only). I also noticed an influx in GitHub stickers in my neighbourhood (which were included with the t-shirt) so I assume there must be a few participants in my hood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apps4Halifax Crime Heatmaps</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/apps4halifax-crime-heatmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 21:02:46 -0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/apps4halifax-crime-heatmaps/</guid>
      <description>I took part in the Apps4Halifax open data contest and won second place in my category with Halifax Crime.
Halifax Crime is an animated heatmap of crime in the city.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>