<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on David Hamp-Gonsalves</title>
    <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on David Hamp-Gonsalves</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 10:17:20 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cargo Bike in Canada</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/cargo-bike-in-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 10:17:20 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/cargo-bike-in-canada/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bakfietsen.com/&#34;&gt;Babboe&lt;/a&gt; cargo bike in Toronto for a year now, this is a review of that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/images/cargo-bike.jpg&#34; class=&#34;center plain&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve ridden the Babboe every day for a year. Its terrific on the ice and works well in deep snow. Its amazingly useful, and gets my daughter to daycare and back each day. It holds about $200 in groceries plus a child. Its easy to peddle and only takes a few minutes to learn to ride (if you can already ride a bicycle).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;good&#34;&gt;Good&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cargo bikes in general are amazingly useful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weathered the Canadian winters well even being stored outdoors under a cover.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The wooden box is beautiful, solid and durible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fenders and chainguard keep you clean and comfortable even in bad weather.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rainhood keeps passengers dry and warm even in the winter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tires are nice but I switched to thinner(35mm) after they wore out which I prefer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bad&#34;&gt;Bad&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although it costs over $3000 the components it uses are low end. A &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.larryvsharry.com/&#34;&gt;Bullitt&lt;/a&gt; is much nicer but at a higher price point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It uses drum brakes which are low maintenence but perform poorly (replaced with higher end ones with minimal improvement).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The peddles are plastic and get slippery in bad weather (replaced).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My brake cables developed rust and had to be replaced with better quality ones.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rain hood attachment is a bit slow to put on but is great if you can leave it on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I bought my Babboe from &lt;a href=&#34;https://curbsidecycle.com/&#34;&gt;Curbside&lt;/a&gt; which is a great shop.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Being the Best</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/the-value-of-being-the-best/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2017 14:12:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/the-value-of-being-the-best/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Training data shapes our current iterations of AI and as they get more competitive so will the search for the best datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While its easy to use training data from many individuals(driving habits for example) which might average out to be the best overall it will be hard to optomize for specific attributes(gas milage, passenger comfort).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this will create new incentives for being the best at mundane activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example it would be ideal if your atonomous car drove like the highest rated, safest, most full efficent uber/lift driver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team dedicated to the perfection of a routine task solely for the sake of generating a dataset that could then be used to train a superior AI for a given usecase could become the next sport like pursuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather then an artists artwork being the final product they sell, the training data could be auctioned off and the artwork itself could be generated as needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CircleCI vs Travis</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/circleci-vs-travis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 23:12:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/circleci-vs-travis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR&lt;/strong&gt;: Just use CircleCI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having used both products in my last two positions I can say that while I once pined for Travis&amp;rsquo;s(then) superior documentation, that stage has passed and I now enthusiastically choose CircleCI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CircleCI&amp;rsquo;s UI is amazing. It feels snappy and well suited to the task. I often find myself waiting for pages to load in Travis. The UI is also branch centric which better supports feature development where as Travis seems project focused and doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit my typical usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CircleCI&amp;rsquo;s ability to parse the test results(which I didn&amp;rsquo;t appreciate this till it was gone) is amazing. Its so nice not to have to scroll though all your tests to see what broke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are other better publicised benefits in the areas of running tests in parallel but for me these two details have the largest impact on my quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should You Move To San Francisco?</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/moving-to-sf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 23:09:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/moving-to-sf/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLDR&lt;/strong&gt;:  Yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My move to SF is 100% a silicon valley stereotype. I wrote an app(eb), was contacted by some startups and large valley companies and a couple weeks later I was on a plane with a 6 month old and my wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coming from Toronto there was almost no cultural transition, except for the dissonance between rich/poor and how strictly each cultural group / archetype stays in their own portion of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first month we stayed in an AirBnb in Oakland which was actually just a really nice backyard shed. The food was great (&lt;a href=&#34;https://lanesplitterpizza.com/&#34;&gt;https://lanesplitterpizza.com/&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://victoryburger.com/&#34;&gt;http://victoryburger.com/&lt;/a&gt;), weather 100% consistent and people friendly but the bus commute was cutting into nights with my family so we moved to the Sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I could cycling to work (best part of my day) and to surf at ocean beach but it came with $3600/month rent (it went for $4000 a year later when we left).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrospectively I would have opted to save some money and live in the east bay. If I was single I would opt for somewhere wretched / small / cheap in the city and aim to get out more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was easy to burn through my moving bonus + salary(double what I made in Toronto) in the first few months but after that the savings do come(albeit slowly and only with diligence).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working conditions were far better then any I had experienced prior. I played guitar in the office music room, learned how to play ping pong, found / rebuilt drones all over the place and generally just had a lot of fun. The work was interesting and it was amazing being around brilliant co-workers. You&amp;rsquo;ll also never have to worry about saying something too technical, geeky or nuanced since it will always be received warmly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;cons&#34;&gt;Cons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The counter to this is: everything is expensive, you&amp;rsquo;ll spend more time at work, you&amp;rsquo;ll get sick of microbrew IPA&amp;rsquo;s, money will loose all meaning and generally things will feel &amp;ldquo;unreal&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ll feel like you&amp;rsquo;ve entered a world that is oddly tailored to you which will only emphasise your feelings of being a muppet. At the same time you&amp;rsquo;ll see the daily negative effects that tech wealth has on the remaining residents which you are now a part of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrospectively it was a positive experience. I&amp;rsquo;m still benefiting from the contacts I made and experience I accrued. The TN visa makes it easy for Canadians to make this move and its in our interest to take advantage of our free trade agreement the politicians worked to put in place.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacktoberfest 2015</title>
      <link>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/hacktoberfest-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 23:14:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://davidhampgonsalves.github.io/post/hacktoberfest-2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I took part in Digital Oceans Hacktoberfest &amp;amp; had a lot of fun. I ended up pushing some PR&amp;rsquo;s to new projects that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have otherwise and got a a t-shirt even though I live in Canada (usually these things are US only). I also noticed an influx in GitHub stickers in my neighbourhood (which were included with the t-shirt) so I assume there must be a few participants in my hood.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>